The man of "True Grit" is back and look who's got him!
Rooster Cogburn is a adventure, drama, western film directed by Stuart Millar.
After a band of drunken thugs overruns a small Indian Nation town, killing Reverend Goodnight and raping the women folk, Eula
Goodnight enlists the aid of US Marshal Cogburn to hunt them down and bring her father's killers to justice.
Reuben J. "Rooster" Cogburn, played by John Wayne.
Eula Goodnight, played by Katharine Hepburn.
Breed, played by Anthony Zerbe.
Hawk, played by Richard Jordan.
Judge Parker, played by John McIntire.
Luke, played by Paul Koslo.
Rooster Cogburn, also known as Rooster Cogburn (...and the Lady), is a 1975 American Western
film directed by Stuart Millar, and starring John Wayne and Katharine Hepburn.
Written by Martha Hyer (who is credited as Martin Julien) and based on the Rooster Cogburn character from Charles Portis' 1968 Western novel
True Grit, the film is a sequel to True Grit (1969), and the second installment overall in the film series of the same name.
The plot details the continuing adventures of Reuben J.
"Rooster" Cogburn, an aging one-eyed lawman, whose badge is suspended due
to his record of routine arrests that end in bloodshed.
He is offered a chance to redeem himself by bringing in a group of bank robbers who have hijacked a wagon shipment of
nitroglycerin, and finds himself aided in his quest by a spinster whose father was killed by the criminals.
The film explores themes of gunslinger, arkansas,
nitroglycerin, sequel, u.s. marshal.
The tone is emotional.